In the last video, you saw how
the Skip-Gram model
allows you to construct
a supervised learning tasks
so you map from
context to target
words and how that allows you
to learn a useful
word embedding.
But the downside of that was
the sock max objective
was slow to compute.
In this video, you see
a modified learning
problem called negative
sampling that allows
you to do something
similar to the skip-gram
model you saw just now,
but with a much more
efficient learning algorithm.
Let's see how you could do that.
Most of the ideas presented in
this video are due
to Thomas Mikolov,
Sasaki, Chen Greco,
and Jeff Dean.
What we're going to do in
this algorithm is create
a new supervised
learning problem.
The problem is, given
a pair of words
like orange and juice,
we're going to predict, is
this a context target pair?
In this example, orange juice
was a positive example.
How about Orange and King?
Well, that's a negative example
so I'm going to write
zero for the target.
What we're going to do is
we're actually going to
sample a context
and a target word.
In this case, we had
orange and juice and
we'll associate that
with a Label 1.
Let's just put word
in the middle.
Then having generated
a positive example,
the positive examples
generated exactly how
we generated it in the previous
videos sample context word,
look around a window of say,
+-10 words, and
pick a target word.
That's how you generate
the first row of
this table with
orange juice one.
Then to generate the
negative examples,
you're going to take the
same context word and
then just pick a word at
random from the dictionary.
In this case, I chose
the word king at
random and label that as zero.
Then let's take
orange and let's pick
another random word from
the dictionary under
the assumption
that if we pick a random word,
it probably won't be associated
with the word orange,
so book, zero.
Let's pick a few others, orange,
maybe just by chance
we'll pick the zero,
and then orange, and
maybe just by chance,
we'll pick the word of and
we'll put a zero there.
Notice that all of these
labeled as zero even though
the word of actually appears
next to orange as well.
To summarize the way we
generated this
dataset is we'll pick
a context word and then
pick a target word
and that is the first
row of this table,
that gives us a
positive example.
Context target, and then
give that a label of one.
Then what we do is for
some number of times,
say k times, we're going to take
the same context words and
then pick random words
from the dictionary.
King, book, the, of,
whatever comes out
at random from
the dictionary and
label all those zero,
and those will be our
negative examples.
It's okay if just by chance,
one of those words we
picked at random from
the dictionary happens
to appear in a window,
in a plus-minus
ten-word windows,
say next to the
context word orange.
Then we're going to create a
supervised learning problem,
where the algorithm inputs x
inputs this pair of words,
and then has to predict
the target label to
predict the output Y.
The problem is really
given a pair of
words like orange and juice,
do you think they
appear together?
Do you think I got
these two words by
sampling two words
close to each other?
Or do you think I got them as
one word from the text and
one word chosen at random
from the dictionary?
Is really to try to distinguish
between these two types of
distributions from which you
might sample a pair of words.
This is how you generate
the training set.
How do you choose Mikolov at
all that recommend
that maybe k is
5-20 for smaller datasets
and if you have a
very large dataset,
then choose k to be
smaller so k=2-5 for
larger datasets
and larger values
of k for smaller datasets.
In this example,
I've just used k=4.
Next, let's describe the
supervised learning model
for learning and
mapping from x-y.
Here was the SoftMax model you
saw from the previous video
and here's the training set we
got from the previous
slide where again,
this is going to be the new
input x and this is going to
be the value of y you're
trying to predict.
To define the model,
I'm going to use this
to denote this with c
for the context word,
this to denote the
possible target word
t and this I'll use
y to denote 01.
This is a context target pair.
What we're going to do
is define a logistic
regression model.
We say that the chance that y=1
given the input c,t pair,
we're going to model this
as basically a logistic
regression model.
But the specific formula we
use is sigmoid applied to
Theta t transpose ec.
The parameters are
similar as before.
You have one parameter
vector Theta
for each possible
target word and
a separate parameter
vector really
the embedding vector for
each possible context word.
We're going to use this formula
to estimate the
probability that y=1.
If you have k examples here.
Then if you can think
of this as having
a k:1 ratio of negative
to positive examples.
For every positive examples,
you will have k
negative examples with
which to train this
logistic regression model.
To draw this as a
neural network,
if the input word is orange,
which is word 6,257,
then what you do is input their
one hot vector passes through E,
do the multiplication to get
the embedding vector 6,257.
Then what you have is really
10,000 possible
logistic regression
classification problems
where one of these
will be the classifier
corresponding to.
Well, is the target word juice
or not. Then there'll
be other words.
For example, there
may be one somewhere
down here which is predicting is
the word king or not
and so on for these
are possible words
in your vocabulary.
Think of this as having
10,000 binary logistic
regression classifiers.
But instead of training all
10,000 of them on
every iteration,
we're only going to
train five of them.
We're going to train the
one corresponding to
the actual target
word we got and then
train four randomly
chosen negative examples,
and this is for the
case where K = 4.
Instead of having one
giant 10,000 way softmax,
which is very
expensive to compute,
we've instead turned it into
10,000 binary
classification problems.
Each of which is quite cheap to
compute and on every iteration,
we're only going to
train five of them,
or more generally, k+1 of them,
with k negative examples and
one positive examples and this
is why the computational
cost of this algorithm
is much lower because you're
updating k+1 binary
classification problems,
which is relatively cheap
to do on every iteration,
rather than updating a 10,000
way softmax classifier.
This technique is called
negative sampling
because what you're
doing is you had a
positive example,
the orange and the juice.
Then you would go
and deliberately
generate a bunch of
negative examples.
We've negative samplings,
hence the negative sampling,
which to train four more of
these binary classifiers,
and on every
iteration you choose
four different random
negative words
with which to train
your algorithm on.
Now, before wrapping up,
one more important detail
of this algorithm is,
how do you choose the
negative examples?
After having chosen the
context word orange,
how do you sample
these words to generate
the negative examples?
One thing you could do is
sample the words in the middle,
the candidate target words.
One thing you could do is
sample it according to
the empirical frequency
of words in your corpus.
Just sample it according
to how often different
words appears.
But the problem with that
is that you end up with
a very high representation
of words like the,
of, and, and so on.
One other extreme
will be let say,
you use one over the vocab_size.
Sample the negative
examples uniformly random.
But that's also very
non representative
of the distribution
of English words.
The authors [inaudible]
reported that empirically
what they found to work best was
to take this heuristic value,
which is a little bit in between
the two extremes of
sampling from the
empirical frequencies,
meaning from whatever is the
observed distribution in
English text to the
uniform distribution,
and what they did
was they sampled
proportional to the frequency
of a word to the
power of three forms.
If f(w_i) is the
observed frequency of
a particular word in
the English language or in
your training set corpus,
then by taking it to
the power of 3/4.
This is somewhere in between
the extreme of taking
uniform distribution and
the other extreme of
just taking whatever was
the observed distribution
in your training set.
I'm not sure this is very
theoretically justified,
but multiple researchers
are now using
this heuristic and it seems
to work decently well.
To summarize, you've
seen how you can
learn word vectors of
a software classified,
but it's very competition
expensive and in this video,
you saw how by changing that to
a bunch of binary
classification problems,
you can very efficiently
learn word vectors,
and if you run this album,
you will be able to learn
pretty good word vectors.
Now, of course,
as is the case in
other areas of deep
learning as well,
there are open source
implementations and there are also
pretrained word vectors that
others have trained and
released online under
permissive licenses.
If you want to get going
quickly on a NLP problem,
it'd be reasonable to download
someone else's word vectors
and use that as a
starting point.
That's it for the
skip-gram model.
In the next video, I
want to share with
you yet another version of
a word embedding
learning algorithm
that is maybe even simpler
than what you've seen so far.
In the next video, let's learn
about the GloVe algorithm.